DAMOLA TAIWO

Barking Wharf square, Barking IG11 7ZW ◆ +447360915648 ◆ khadijahbadmus024@gmail.com

Web: www.github.com/deejarh ◆ LinkedIn: https://shorturl.at/diKQ2

https://badmus-damola-taiwo.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a highly proficient frontend developer with over three years of invaluable experience in the fintech/credit Industry, consistently delivering exceptional user experiences for a range of web applications. I have successfully harnessed an impressive array of cutting-edge technologies, including VueJs, Nuxt, React, JavaScript, Typescript, GraphQL, REST, NodeJs, Tailwind CSS, and HTML, to fulfill complex functional requirements across a diverse spectrum of Fintech/credit products.

WORK HISTORY

Frontend Engineer (Remote), 01/2022 - Current

Torus Mara - Delaware, USA- Remote

Torus Mara provides modern financial services for global institutions, corporations, and SMEs operating across emerging markets. My accomplishments include the following:

- Co-led Torus Mara frontend team as founding member, collaboratively developing business app's code base from scratch. Instrumental in scaling the team from two members to six, efficiently managing five distinct products within the app, generating a monthly transaction volume of \$20m.
- Executed the end-to-end development and successful launch of Omni, an e-commerce platform, managing frontend UI development, integration of third-party SDK (Collect), and backend endpoint consumption for both business-side and customer-side UI.
- Spearheaded the creation of an Admin dashboard, streamlining business data management and empowering administrators with oversight of sign-ups, account activation/deactivation, and efficient management of pending KYCs.
- Developed a versatile FX terminal enabling two-way transactions supporting NGN and GHS to USD, along with assets like USDT. The terminal facilitates fee computation and real-time exchange rate calculations. Currently servicing over 32 registered businesses, with integrated admin tracking via the dashboard to monitor transaction statuses seamlessly.
- Developed a 7-step KYC form for new businesses' compliance, allowing progress saving and continuation. Included seamless biometric verification using a third-party integration, smoothly transitioning users to the next form step upon completion.
- Created an onboarding guide on Confluence for new engineers that highlights setup and configuration instructions using our single sign-on Identity verification tool. The guide also includes running a local instance of our web application.

Tech stack: Vue (2 & 3), Vuex, React, Typescript, Javascript, RestAPI, ElementUi, Nuxt, TailwindCss, HTML, SASS, Git, Github Action (CI/CD), Sentry (Error monitoring), Figma, Mixpanel (Event tracking), AWS.

Frontend Developer, 07/2021 - 12/2021

BFREE - Lagos, Nigeria

BFREE is a credit management company that focuses on consumers' financial health by building products that make collection processes in Africa more scalable, efficient, and user-friendly. My accomplishments include the following:

- Improved data security by implementing a role-based access control (RBAC) system in the CRM, resulting in a 100% reduction in unauthorized data access
- Boosted agent productivity by 2x through the implementation of a notification system that alerted agents about newly assigned customers in the CRM
- Streamlined customer payment evidence processing by introducing a View/Download feature in the CRM, resulting in a 100% decrease in the time and cost required for manual uploads
- Collaborated with a team of 3 frontend developers to enhance the user experience of the CRM by incorporating frequently used features and implementing privacy measures, leading to a 30% increase in monthly revenue
- Strengthened the stability of the CRM application by developing Jest tests for utility functions, minimizing the risk of breaking changes when new features are added.
- Performed manual and automated testing to ensure stability across range of devices and browsers.

Tech stack: Vue2, Javascript, GraphQl, Vuetify, HTML, CSS, Git.

Frontend Developer Intern, 01/2021 - 06/2021

Certified Internet Web Professional

BFREE - Lagos, Nigeria

- Collaborated with a team of two to develop the BFREE website, enhancing brand visibility and attracting potential customers
- Contributed to building and maintaining the company's Self-service portal, enabling customers to effortlessly manage their loan portfolio
- Implemented new features and maintained the company's CRM system within a team, improving customer relationship management and streamlining internal processes.

Tech stack: Vue2, Javascript, GraphQl, Vuetify, HTML, CSS, Git.

| — Skills — |
|------------------------------|
| • Jest |
| • Sass |
| Typescript |
| • JQuery |
| • Firebase |
| • SQL |
| • Figma |
| |
| |
| - Education - |
| |
| - Languages - |
| |
| |
| CERTIFICATIONS |
| |